FRANK GAETE

Frank.gaete1@gmail.com • frankgaete1.github.io/portfolio/ • Palm Beach Gardens, FL USA

OVERVIEW & OBJECTIVE

With over 20 years of experience in user interface and user experience design, I've dedicated my career to creating thoughtful, human-centered digital products that solve real-world problems. I've led and contributed to design initiatives across a wide range of industries and companies (early-stage startups to global Fortune 500 companies) bringing deep expertise in UI/UX strategy, user research, product design, and front-end collaboration. My passion for design has only grown stronger over the years, fueled by a commitment to continuous learning, cross-functional collaboration, and delivering meaningful experiences that put people first.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I've held senior design roles including UX Architect, Experience/Product Designer, and Director, leading and executing design work across browser-based and native mobile applications. My experience spans B2B and B2C, consumer-facing platforms, and complex enterprise SaaS systems.

I bring a 360-degree perspective to human-centered design, shaped by years of hands-on practice in user research, interaction design, content design, and design systems. Known as a collaborative leader and advocate for users, I combine strategic thinking with practical execution to create experiences that are functional, elegant and deeply aligned to user needs and business goals. My 20+ years in the field have equipped me with the ability to navigate complexity, mentor teams, and consistently deliver high-impact design solutions.

CORE SKILL AREAS

Ideation, sketching, wireframing	Adobe Creative Cloud	Agile, JIRA, Confluence
Figma, Adobe XD, UXpin, Axure,	HTML, CSS	Project/team managemen
Sketch, Photoshop	UX Research	Cross team collaboration
Responsive design, native mobile		

PERFORMANCE HIGHLIGHTS

- □ Lead design for the new "Payment Center" feature allowing TD Bank customers to make and schedule credit card payments using TD or non-TD payment accounts.
- □ Helped create successful user centered design systems to provide consistent UI/UX across multi-application platforms for financial, energy, human capital and mass transit industry industries.
- □ Defined and set standards and methods for UX research; UI/UX design and development; collaborations with stakeholders/clients; and ensured consistency across product design and corporate communications.
- □ Helped drive new UI/UX design and development throughout financial industry applications for institutions including JP Morgan Chase, Fidelity, Charles Schwab, Wells Fargo, TD Bank, and others.
- □ Built and managed teams including a highly successful team of 10 UI/UX designer-developers at Broadridge.
- □ Proved the value and benefits of engaging the UI/UX team before application development. While at Broadridge, this resulted in a re-structured SDLC process where projects are first prototyped by the UI/UX team in a fully agile process which increased efficiency and provided significant time and cost savings.
- Designed a first-of-its-kind Investor Communication Portal for Broadridge's financial institution clients. This helped maintain relationships with several large financial institution clients, saving hundreds of thousands of dollars in annual revenue and attract new clients.
- □ Helped design ecommerce/shopping cart journeys from custom to popular CMS platforms such as Squarespace and WordPress
- Successfully defined, designed and executed UX research studies to inform and guide design to optimize user experiences

FRANK GAETE

Frank.gaete1@gmail.com • frankgaete1.github.io/portfolio/ • Palm Beach Gardens, FL USA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TD Bank

Sr. UX Designer, Aug 2021 – present, Remote

- Design interfaces and experiences for client facing products and services
- Develop wireframes, visual designs, user flows/journeys using Figma, Adobe XD
- Plan and design UX research goals and prototypes; analyze data to guide design enhancement recommendations
- Align responsive browser with native mobile (iOS, Android) as closely as possible
- Collaborate with pod members (PO, scrum master, devs, QA, content designers and others); cross team members and enterprise UX designers to ensure consistency across products and platforms

NextEra/Florida Power & Light

Sr. UX Designer/Researcher, Jan 2020 – Jul 2021, Jupiter FL

- Designed interfaces, experiences and content for nuclear power enterprise applications
- Planned and executed UX research; analyzed data to guide design enhancement recommendations; helped standardize UX research methods and processes for future testing
- Developed new design patterns and workflows using Adobe XD, Sketch, and UXpin
- Collaborated with nuclear division team members; product owners and enterprise UX designers

Clever Devices

UI/UX Architect, Sep 2017 – Dec 2019, Woodbury NY

- * Designed interfaces and experiences across several major product groups for desktop, responsive and mobile applications as per requirements, business goals and user research
- * Promoted the need and value of UX research early in the design process; defined and performed research processes and methodologies including usability testing, interviews, surveys, metrics and results driven design enhancement recommendations
- * Designed and defined pattern libraries, style guides, UI/UX policies; software and hardware recommendations
- * Collaborated with various teams to ensure UX and content design consistency across products and corporate communications

Freelance

UI/UX Architect Consultant, Feb - Aug 2017, Coram NY

Frank.gaete1@gmail.com • frankgaete1.github.io/portfolio/ • Palm Beach Gardens, FL USA

Valiant Solutions (now Trackforce)

UI/UX Director, Jul 2016 - Feb 2017, Woodbury NY

- Provided overall UI/UX design for entire SaaS platform across desktop and mobile devices
- Led ideation sessions with executives, dev leads, business analysts, art director, project manager and other stakeholders; conceptualized various design ideas via wireframes, workflows, mockups and HTML/CSS prototypes
- Worked with Creative Director and other Marketing team members to ensure alignment across web apps and corporate communications and redesigned corporate site using WordPress
- Created, maintained and communicated UI/UX policies including design; HTML and CSS coding; design/development approaches; cross browser testing; responsive web design; HTML email; accessibility standards; continuous improvement and more
- UX research including usability test development, surveys, analyze usage metrics, set goals, organize and communicate results/feedback, document UI/UX recommendations and more

Broadridge Financial Solutions

Lead UI/UX Designer-Architect, Apr 2011 – Jul 2016, Edgewood NY

- Converted business requirements and user research into sketches, wireframes, high fidelity mockups, HTML-CSS-jQuery prototypes for multiple projects
- Created, maintained and communicated UI/UX policies including design; design/development approaches; supported browsers; responsive web design; HTML email; accessibility standards
- Provided creative direction and technical UI/UX guidance for desktop and mobile, application platforms
- Worked with financial application teams including tax, transfer agency, shareholder, banks, brokers, shared data services, corporate governance, proxy voting, mutual funds, universal e-delivery
- Collaborated with executives; product managers; developers; BAs and other stakeholders to successfully meet UI/UX requirements

OTHER EXPERIENCE (1997-2009)

- CA Technologies (Computer Associates): Web Developer, Islandia NY, Nov 2009 Mar 2011
- The Creative Group: Web Site Designer / Developer, Rockville Center NY, Dec 2006 Oct 2009
- Veritas Laboratories: Senior Designer / Developer / Project Manager, Bohemia NY, Sep 2000 Oct 2006
- **Dowling College**: Web Services Administrator, Oakdale NY, Jun 1999 Sep 2000
- theglobe.com: Web Producer/Developer, Manhattan NY, Jun 1998 Jun 1999
- Channel21 Productions: Webmaster/Technical Manager, Miller Place NY, Mar 1997 May 1998

EDUCATION

Hofstra University / Dowling College

Internet Architecture, Client/Server systems

Adelphi University, Garden City

B.A. Social Science

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Spanish, fluent

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

US Army Reserve. Highest Rank: Sergeant. Honorable Discharge

FRANK GAETE

Frank.gaete1@gmail.com • frankgaete1.github.io/portfolio/ • Palm Beach Gardens, FL USA